

Summary

I am a Full-Stack Web Developer adept in front-end and back-end solutions. I've worked with an assortment of technologies including Javascript, React, HTML/CSS, SQL and more. I am also able to effectively self-manage during independent work as well as collaborate on projects and lead teams to complete tasks.

Employment

From Lab 2 Fulfillment

Remote Jan. 2023 to Current

Software Engineer

- Mainly using React, JS, Node, and Express, I created several new full-stack apps to my employers specifications.
- Used Agile workflow to collaborate with colleagues and git for source control.
- Analyzed code written by others in several languages to find and fix bugs or update code base.
- · Deployed apps using Google Cloud Repositories and Cloud run to deploy Docker containers onto the web.

Various Employers

Beamsville, ON 2022 to Current

Freelance Web Developer

- Built, updated, and deployed several websites and web applications for various employers.
- Used a variety of coding languages to deliver clean, functional code in a timely manner.

Grand Niagara

Niagara Falls, ON 2015 to 2022

Maintenance Supervisor

- Managed a team of employees and led the completion of various projects.
- Collaborated with management to increase worker efficiency in certain areas by up to 25%.

Concentrix

Niagara Falls, ON 2020 to 2020

Technical Support Advisor

- Handled a variety of customer requests and dealt with any new issues as they arose.
- · Adapted and learned constantly for continued efficiency on calls.

Projects

Simpli

Simpli is a team-based project tracking productivity app. Projects are mapped through a list of deliverables, each containing its own list of tasks.

Front-end: React, JS, CSS, HTML

Back-end: Node, Express, SQL

Interview Scheduler

Interview Scheduler is a Single Page Application built for creating and tracking student interviews.

Front-end: React, JS, CSS, HTML

Back-end: Node, Express, SQL

Test: Jest, Storybook, Cypress

Resource Haven

Resource Haven allows learners to save learning resources (i.e. urls) like tutorials, blogs and videos in a central place that is publicly available to any user.

Front-end: HTML, CSS, JS, EJS, Sass, JQuery

Back-end: Node, Express, SQL

WOGSA Redesign

Contract for a redesign that turned an out of date website into a modern single-page responsive site. Stack: HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery

Ongoing Property Booking Project

Contract to create a single page booking app for a property owned by the client.

Front-end: React, JS, CSS, HTML

Back-End: Node. Express. PostgreSOL

Volunteering

Queen's Model Parliament · Coordinator Ottawa 2018 to 2019

Queen's Alma Mater Society · Campaign Aide Kingston, ON

2018 to 2019

Rotary Club · Volunteer Grimsby, ON 2012 to 2015

Contact

■ nealeptaylor@gmail.com

nealetaylor.com

905-329-6340

♥ Toronto

in nealeptaylor

○ NealePT

Skills

FRONT-END

Javascript

Ruby

HTML

CSS React.JS

FIS

JQuery

BootStrap

SASS/SCSS

MaterialUI

TailwindCSS

BACK-END

Node.JS

Rails Aiax

Express

SYSTEMS, DATABASES

PostgreSQL

MySQL

Docker

Google Cloud

uit

TESTING

Mocha Chai

Jest

Cypress

Storybook

Education

Lighthouse Labs

2022

2021

Diploma Full-Stack Web Development

Juno College Front-End Web Development Course

Queen's University

2015 to 2019

BA (Honours) Political Studies